Independence Historical Society records, Inclusive: 1836-2020, undated, Bulk: 1965-1994
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
Independence Historical Society records
Inclusive: 1836-2020, undated, Bulk: 1965-1994
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
3796
Independence Historical Society
6 document boxes.
The Independence Historical Society records consist of manuscripts authored by or about the Independence Historical Society and historic preservation in Washington County. These papers contain correspondence, financial, legal, literary, and photographic materials.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
The Independence Historical Society is the oldest historic preservation organization still active in Independence, Texas. Following in the footsteps of earlier groups, such as the Independence Homecoming Association and the Baylor Historical Society, the group has always had close ties to Baylor University. The society today owns and operates the John P. Coles House and Asbury-Daniels House, both early Texas houses in Independence, as well as undertake other preservation and beautification projects about the village.
Started in 1965, the society was dedicated to historic preservation around Independence, Texas. During the 1960s the society kept busy erecting Texas Historical Markers around the village. To raise the money for these historical markers, the group sold notepaper and commemorative plates embellished with drawings of historic buildings from the area. In 1969 the society took on the project of restoring the Nancy Lea burial vault across from Independence Baptist Church. Applications for historical markers and various manuscripts from selling notepaper and commemorative plates are preserved within the collection, along with articles of incorporation and other documents from the society’s founding.
The society worked on additional projects in the 1970s. These included clearing and preserving the Independence cemetery, restoring the Nancy Lea vault across from Independence Baptist Church, adding a gate at the cemetery and a flagpole at the town square, and placing 5 more historical markers around the village. An essay about preserving the Nancy Lea vault is housed in the records.
During the 1970s the group also acquired their first historic house. The John P. Coles House, which was moved from its original site to a spot near Old Baylor Park, was restored in the early 1970s. The society also began a popular docent program to provide tours of the Coles House. In 1975 someone ran into the Coles House with a vehicle, making extensive repairs to the east side of the house necessary. A thorough restoration survey of the Coles House, together with other documents from this period are preserved within this collection.
In the 1980s the society took on another early Texas house, the Asbury-Daniels House. This structure was moved to the current location, and was also staffed with docents and open to the public. Among other documents, a restoration proposal on the Asbury-Daniels House from this period is housed in these records.
In the late 1990s, the Independence Historical Society was joined by another organization in helping to preserve historical Independence. The Independence Preservation Trust, formed in 1999, also began preservation efforts around the town.
At the start of the 21st century, the Independence Historical Society continued their work at historic Independence by keeping their historic houses open to the public through docent-led tours. Baylor University also experienced a renaissance in their interest in Independence, the town that had once hosted Baylor University’s original campus. Baylor partnered with the Independence Preservation Trust to open a historical park on the site of the former men’s campus in 2006, and in 2010 Baylor partnered with the Independence Historical Society to open the historic Adobe Toalson house as the Independence Visitor Center. The Independence Historical Society continues today in their historic preservation efforts through regular meetings, volunteer docent-led tours of their two historic homes, and providing information to the public at the Independence Visitor Center.
Scope and Content
The Independence Historical Society records begins in 1836 with copies of general legal documents, and ends in 2020 with correspondence.
Many materials were either produced by or for the Independence Historical Society. A sizable amount pertains to historic preservation efforts in the broader Washington County context. It is likely that some members of the Independence Historical Society were also members of other local historic preservation organizations.
This collection was extensively damaged before arrival at The Texas Collection. This partial destruction included rodent droppings, urine, and chewing along the edges of many manuscripts. Due to this damage, the decision was made to copy every document in the collection, file the copies, and deaccession the originals.
On 2012 April 25 original (non-copied) materials were added to the collection. These documents were not contaminated like the originals in the collection were.
Arrangement
Prior to this finding aid, the collection had never been processed. Much of the collection was organized by year, but extensive reorganization was necessary. The original order was kept most closely in the minute books.
Currently the Independence Historical Society records are arranged in five series: I. Correspondence, II. Legal Documents, III. Financial Documents, IV. Literary Productions, and V. Photographic Materials.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 3796.
Related Resources
Related references
Independence Preservation Trust. “Early Texas Homes: John P. Coles Cabin & Independence Log House.” Accessed 2011 October 26.
“New Independence Center Will Be Dedicated Friday.” Brenham Banner-Press, 2010 April 10. Accessed 2011 October 26.
Index Terms
Subjects (Organizations)
Baylor University (Independence, Tex.) -- History.; Independence Historical Society (Brenham, Tex.).
Places
Independence (Tex.) -- History -- Societies, etc.; Independence (Tex.).; Texas -- Photographs.; Washington County (Tex.) -- History -- Societies, etc.
Subjects
Historic buildings -- Texas-- Independence -- Pictorial works.
Genres
Agendas (administrative records); Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Correspondence.; Essays.; Financial records.; Financial statements.; Legal documents.; Maps.; Newsletters.; Pamphlets.; Programs.
- Correspondence, 1964-2020, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Excellent.
  Biography/Profile
  Correspondence to and from leaders and members of the Independence Historical Society. Many of the letters have to do with reminding members about various upcoming functions of the society. All original manuscripts were copied during processing, with only the copies filed due to extensive damage to the originals. Series is in excellent condition.
  - Correspondence, 1964-1965 July (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1965 August-September (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1965 October-November (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1965 December (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1970 January-March (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1970 April-August (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1972 August (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1972 December-1973 May (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: (1 of 4), 1973 June (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: (2 of 4), 1973 June (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: (3 of 4), 1973 June (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: (4 of 4), 1973 June (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1973 July-1976 February (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1977 March-September 8 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1977 September 26-1984 May (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1984 August-1989 January 10 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1989 January19-June (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1989 July-September (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1989 October-1992 March (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1992 April-1997 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1997 December-1998 July (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1997 September-November (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence: (1 of 3), undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence: (2 of 3), undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence: (3 of 3), undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence: Postcards, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Legal Documents, 1836-1998, undated; 2
  Legal manuscripts detailing the society’s founding, and inventories of historical artifacts in the John P. Coles House. Other documents pertain to the insurance taken out by the society for their properties and a survey of the town square to establish boundaries and ownership. All original manuscripts were copied during processing, with only the copies filed due to extensive damage to the originals.
  - General, 1836-1998, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Articles of Incorporation, 1965-1988, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Articles of Incorporation: Independence, 1838-1980, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Survey: Independence Town Square, 1838- 1985, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Deeds, 1914-1983 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Insurance, 1976-1989 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Insurance, 1990-1994 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Insurance, 1995-1997, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Inventories, 1989, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Inventories (1 of 2), undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Inventories (2 of 2), undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Financial Documents, 1861-1998, undated; 3
  Series contains financial information pertaining to the Independence Historical Society, their historic properties, and various fundraising activities. All original manuscripts were copied during processing, with only the copies filed due to extensive damage to the originals.
  - General, 1989-1991, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Taxes, 1984-1995 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Bills, Receipts, Statements, 1861-1971 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Bills, Receipts, Statements, 1972-1995 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Bills, Receipts, Statements, 1968-1988 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Treasurer’s Reports, 1965-1973 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Treasurer’s Reports, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Treasurer’s Reports, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Treasurer’s Reports, 1991-1992 April (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Treasurer’s Reports, 1992 June-1998 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Bank Statements, 1983-1984 August (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Bank Statements, 1984 September-1988 August (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Bank Statements, 1988 September-1991 October (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Bank Statements, 1991 November-1992 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Treasurer’s Report: United Daughters of the Confederacy, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Literary Productions, 1899-2011, undated; 4
  This series includes essays, membership information, docent materials, pamphlets, essays, minutes, and clippings pertaining to the Independence Historical Society and historic preservation efforts in Washington County. All original manuscripts were copied during processing, with only the copies filed due to extensive damage to the originals.
  - General, 1889, 1986-1998, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Restoration Survey: John P. Coles House, 1973, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Restoration Proposal: Asbury-Daniels House, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Maps, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Membership Lists, 1986-1988 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Membership Lists, 1989-1999, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Meeting Agendas, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Meeting Agendas, 1989-1998 February (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Meeting Agendas, 1998 March-October, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Historical Marker Applications, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Historical Marker Applications, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Pamphlets, 1973, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Pamphlets, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Pamphlets: Brenham, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Pamphlets: Burton, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Pamphlets: Chappell Hill, 1980-1987 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Pamphlets: Washington County Heritage Society, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Pamphlets: “Greetings, Baylor College for Women”, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Programs, 1965-1969 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Programs, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Programs, 1973-1995 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Programs, 1996-1998 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Programs, 2000, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Printed Materials: Docent Training (1 of 2), 1988 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Printed Materials: Docent Training (2 of 2), 1988 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Printed Materials: Docent Training, 2000, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Printed Materials: Docent Evaluations, 1990-1993 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Printed Materials: Docent Evaluations, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Broadsides, 1970-1994 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Broadsides, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Historical Markers: Independence (1 of 2), 2011 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Historical Markers: Independence (2 of 2), 2011 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Historical Markers: Washington County (1 of 4), 2011 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Historical Markers: Washington County (2 of 4), 2011 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Historical Markers: Washington County (3 of 4), 2011 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Historical Markers: Washington County (4 of 4), 2011 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - General: Other Historical Societies, 1967-1990, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Lists: Contact Information, 1991-1994, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Notes, 1970, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Notes: Mrs. Earl Allen (1 of 7), 1965-1971 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Notes: Mrs. Earl Allen (2 of 7), 1965-1971 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Notes: Mrs. Earl Allen (3 of 7), 1965-1971 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Notes: Mrs. Earl Allen (4 of 7), 1965-1971 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Notes: Mrs. Earl Allen (5 of 7), 1965-1971 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Notes: Mrs. Earl Allen (6 of 7), 1965-1971 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Notes: Mrs. Earl Allen (7 of 7), 1965-1971 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Vendors List: Founder’s Day, undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Guest Book (1 of 3), 1991-1997 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Guest Book (2 of 3), 1991-1997 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Guest Book (2 of 3), 1991-1997 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Membership Newsletters, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Membership Newsletters, 1986 February-June (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Membership Newsletters, 1986 September-1989 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Membership Newsletters, 1991-1998, undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Membership Newsletters (1 of 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Membership Newsletters (2 of 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Essays: General, 1945, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Essays: Independence, 1970, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Essays: John P. Coles House (1 of 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Essays: John P. Coles House (2 of 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Essays: Politics in Washington County, 1986, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Essays: Historic Homes in Washington County, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Essays: Davis Family (1 of 2), 1899-1900 (copies), undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Essays: Davis Family (2 of 2), 1899-1900 (copies), undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Essays: Albert G. Haynes, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Essays: La Bahía Trail, 1899 (copy), undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Essays: Hunt-Hardy House (1 of 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Essays: Hunt-Hardy House (2 of 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Essays: “Masonic Lodges of Washington County”, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Essays: “Institutions of Learning” (1 of 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Essays: “Institutions of Learning” (2 of 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Essays: “Dr. Horace G. Clark”, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Essays: “Burton Farmer’s Gin”, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Essays: “Early Presbyterianism in Texas”, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Essays: “My Parents and Background”, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Essays: “The Unrealized Blessings of a Large Family”, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Essays: “Politician on Horseback” (1 of 2), 1996 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Essays: “Politician on Horseback” (2 of 2), 1996 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Essays: “Glimpses of History 1880-1940”, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Accessions: John P. Coles House (1 of 5), 1973-1977 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Accessions: John P. Coles House (2 of 5), 1973-1977 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Accessions: John P. Coles House (3 of 5), 1973-1977 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Accessions: John P. Coles House (4 of 5), 1973-1977 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Accessions: John P. Coles House (5 of 5), 1973-1977 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Accessions: John P. Coles House (1 of 3), 1984-1989 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Accessions: John P. Coles House (2 of 3), 1984-1989 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Accessions: John P. Coles House (3 of 3), 1984-1989 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Donations: Asbury-Daniels House (1 of 3), 1984-1989 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Donations: Asbury-Daniels House (2 of 3), 1984-1989 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Donations: Asbury-Daniels House (3 of 3), 1984-1989 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 1: 1965-1971 (1 of 14), 1965-1966 January (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 1: 1965-1971 (2 of 14), 1966 February-August (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 1: 1965-1971 (3 of 14), 1966 September-1967 March (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 1: 1965-1971 (4 of 14), 1967 April-October (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 1: 1965-1971 (5 of 14), 1967 November-1968 June (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 1: 1965-1971 (6 of 14), 1968 July-October (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 1: 1965-1971 (7 of 14), 1968 December-1969 May (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 1: 1965-1971 (8 of 14), 1969 June-November (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 1: 1965-1971 (9 of 14), 1969 December-1970 June (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 1: 1965-1971 (10 of 14), 1970 July-1971 February (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 1: 1965-1971 (11 of 14), 1971 March-November (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 1: 1965-1971 (12 of 14), 1966-1971 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 1: 1965-1971 (13 of 14), 1966-1979 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 1: 1965-1971 (14 of 14), 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 2: 1972-1974 (1 of 10), 1972 January-June (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 2: 1972-1974 (2 of 10), 1972 July-November (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 2: 1972-1974 (3 of 10), 1972 January-1973 March (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 2: 1972-1974 (4 of 10), 1973 April (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 2: 1972-1974 (5 of 10), 1973 May-June (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 2: 1972-1974 (6 of 10), 1973 August-December (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 2: 1972-1974 (7 of 10), 1974 January-February (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 2: 1972-1974 (8 of 10), 1974 March-May (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 2: 1972-1974 (9 of 10), 1974 June-August (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 2: 1972-1974 (10 of 10), 1974 September-November (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 3: 1975-1977 (1 of 8), 1975 January-February (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 3: 1975-1977 (2 of 8), 1975 March-May (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 3: 1975-1977 (3 of 8), 1975 September-October (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 3: 1975-1977 (4 of 8), 1975 October-1976 January (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 3: 1975-1977 (5 of 8), 1976 March-May (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 3: 1975-1977 (6 of 8), 1976 June-September (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 3: 1975-1977 (7 of 8), 1977 January-March (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 3: 1975-1977 (8 of 8), 1977 April-November (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 4: 1978-1982 (1 of 8), 1978 January-April (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 4: 1978-1982 (2 of 8), 1978 May-September (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 4: 1978-1982 (3 of 8), 1978 October-1979 April (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 4: 1978-1982 (4 of 8), 1979 May-November (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 4: 1978-1982 (5 of 8), 1980 February-April (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 4: 1978-1982 (6 of 8), 1980 May-1981 January (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 4: 1978-1982 (7 of 8), 1981 February-September (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 4: 1978-1982 (8 of 8), 1981 October-1982 January (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 5: 1989-1993 (1 of 10), 1989 January-May (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 5: 1989-1993 (2 of 10), 1988 June-July (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 5: 1989-1993 (3 of 10), 1988 August-1989 January (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 5: 1989-1993 (4 of 10), 1989 March-May (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 5: 1989-1993 (5 of 10), 1989 May-September (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 5: 1989-1993 (6 of 10), 1989 October-1990 January (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 5: 1989-1993 (7 of 10), 1990 February-June (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 5: 1989-1993 (8 of 10), 1990 July-December (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 5: 1989-1993 (9 of 10), 1991 January-1992 September (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 5: 1989-1993 (10 of 10), 1992 October-1993 February (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 6: 1997-1998 (1 of 4), 1997 January-June (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 6: 1997-1998 (2 of 4), 1997 July-1998 January (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 6: 1997-1998 (3 of 4), 1998 February-June (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 6: 1997-1998 (4 of 4), 1998 August-October (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Minutes: Minute Book 7: 1999, 1999 February-September (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Minutes: Loose Minutes: 1965-1987 (1 of 6), 1965-1966 March (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Minutes: Loose Minutes: 1965-1987 (2 of 6), 1966 April-1984 September 7 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Minutes: Loose Minutes: 1965-1987 (3 of 6), 1984 September 14-1985 October (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Minutes: Loose Minutes: 1965-1987 (4 of 6), 1985 November-1987 January (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Minutes: Loose Minutes: 1965-1987 (5 of 6), 1987 February-June (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Minutes: Loose Minutes: 1965-1987 (6 of 6), 1987 July-November (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Minutes: Loose Minutes, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Minutes: Compact Disk, 1965-circa 1990 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Clippings: Independence, 1931-1988 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Clippings: Independence, 1989-1998 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Clippings: Independence, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Clippings: Washington County, 1931-1965 November (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Clippings: Washington County, 1965 December-1966 May (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Clippings: Washington County, 1966 August-1967 April (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Clippings: Washington County, 1967 June-1969 July (Box 6, Folder 27)